imo.org 2014-12-22

# IMO | Privacy Policy

This statement discloses the privacy policy of the International Maritime Organization (IMO). By submitting your information and using our website, you consent to the collection, storage and processing of your personal information by us in the manner set out in the policy. IMO reserves the right to change the policy at any time by posting any changes here. Your continued use of the website after a change is made constitutes acceptance of the policy as modified.

## What personally identifiable information does IMO collect on its site, and how is it used?

IMO does not collect any personally identifiable information about you unless you voluntarily submit it to us (for example, by registering to receive IMO News or our IMO Publishing newsletter) or submit it to us as part of the process of purchasing publications from our e-commerce site. IMO is the sole owner of the information collected on this site. We will not pass this information to others except as disclosed in our privacy policy.

IMO assumes no responsibility for the data-collection and data-use practices of third parties that process online credit-card transactions.

**IMO News**

When you subscribe to our quarterly magazine IMO News, in print or online, we ask for basic information, so that the magazine may be sent to the right person, and certain additional pieces of information for statistical and marketing purposes. We do not pass our mailing list on to third parties under any circumstances. You may opt out of receiving IMO News at any time by sending an e-mail to [sales@imo.org](mailto:sales@imo.org) (electronic edition) or [imonews@imo.org](mailto:imonews@imo.org) (print edition), giving your name, subscriber reference (if appropriate) and (e-mail) address.

**IMO Publishing newsletter**

When you subscribe to our IMO Publishing newsletter, we ask for basic information, so that the magazine may be sent to the right person, and certain additional pieces of information for statistical and marketing purposes. We do not pass our mailing list on to third parties under any circumstances. You may opt out of receiving the newsletter at any time by sending an e-mail to [sales@imo.org](mailto:sales@imo.org) giving your name and (e-mail) address.

## Purchases from IMO

As part of the process of purchasing publications, including e-books and other electronic items, and subscribing to online products, users are asked to provide information on our e-commerce site. This information may include contact details and financial information (for example, credit-card details). It is used for billing purposes; to fulfill customers’ orders; to handle problems in order processing; to inform customers of new editions, supplements and errata for titles they have purchased; and to remind subscribers and distributors before their subscriptions expire.

## Cookies

IMO’s website uses cookies. A cookie is a piece of data stored on the user's hard drive containing information about the user. Usage of a cookie is in no way linked to any personally identifiable information. Cookies are only used to obtain non-personal information to improve the online experience. No other information is stored in these cookies. You can set your browser to notify you when you receive a cookie and delete any cookies you receive.

## Log files

IMO uses the IP address from your internet connection to analyse trends, administer the site, track users' movements and gather broad demographic information for aggregate use. IP addresses are not linked to any personally identifiable information.

## Links

The IMO website contains links to other sites. We are not responsible for the privacy practices of other sites.​
